on in the summertime. Uh relatively calm
week, earnings continue to come through
and uh that will be a theme for the rest
of the year. Regardless of uh what
you're reading and hearing, the earnings
is going to be the major story. I'll get
into um some specific things on AI and
some things that I've talked about in
the past regarding the earnings and the
profit margins. Uh, China came to the
market today um, after I had heard
people talk about how China wasn't in an
AI race with the US. Uh, for those of
you who are listening to people say
that, that that is not true. Um, and
yes, I've read the Deep Seek interview.
I've read the Xiinping interview. Uh,
they're in a race for a lot of good
reasons, too. Um if you believe that the
dollar reserve status has been a benefit
uh owning a crypto becomes kind of the
most important thing in the world going
forward. So everyone from a national
basis that can compete would compete and
that really makes it a two-horse race
between China and the US with two
different strategic approaches. I'll go
through some of that. uh Google
earnings. I'll get into the nitty-gritty
of it um and just go through the facts
uh in terms of not just the negative
free cash flow which makes its way
around Twitter for the quarter, but also
the incredibly rising backlog and the
cloud growth uh short-term noise versus
noise versus long-term flow. I'm going
to try to give you guys a perspective on
what you should be thinking about in AI
regardless of whether this slowdown that
we've been in in terms of, you know, the
post parabolic move consolidation,
whether it lasts another six weeks or
six months doesn't really matter. It
doesn't change the long-term flow of AI.
Uh, a new prompt on the mosaic side that
I spent some time working on this week.
Kimmy K3, I go into more details. I
released a new paper on Vera Rubin which
is now coming out. You've got the rise
in oil prices again. Um so we get to
talk about that and the clarity act.
But let's get started. So for the week
after all the stuff whether it was a big
up move, big down move the S&P was down
61 basis points. So again, what I like
to look at is massive move up
and we've now had basically, you know,
two up weeks, then two down weeks, two
up. We're consolidating a big move
higher at this point. That's the way the
weekly moves are going. That may change,
but for right now, I'd go with that. Uh
Q's down one and a half%. IWM,
the fourth week in a row with a sub 1%
absolute return move. So it's been down
four weeks in a row, less than 1% each
move. You don't see that kind of
movement anywhere. So V's been coming
down and we've seen small caps any way
do much better than the broader market
at this point, which to me is a symbol
of
earning strength uh and breath and
broadening out. Momentum, tech momentum
after just a gruesome four weeks. Uh we
got a bounce 8% for the week. V for the
week was less. Here's the move. We went
up, then we came back down. This is the
tech mo chart. Industrial MO went right
back down towards the lows. The white
line here is Mo in general. After you
have a massive move of this size with
the V. The way I've shown it, I find
very little chance that we go straight
back up. If we did go back up, I think
it's going to take some time. I think
it'll take the whole second half of the
year. Uh I believe we'll be going
through a period of chop where the
companies that beat like the
[clears throat]
Intels, the Microns, the stuff like
that. They'll find a bottom and they'll
be able to build something. And then
you'll have some other companies that
don't meet the bar. Uh on the flip side,
what helped Mo this week on one side
tech was the fact that Google sold off.
That was really the biggest part of the
jump here uh was the Google falling
because again the hyperscalers been on
the negative side. As you look at the
rest of MO again very quiet, not much
going on. This is really a AI side. This
is the equal weight ETF which as I
mentioned you can't even tell there's
anything going on there volatility wise.
We're just kind of bouncing around.
Thematic portfolio was up one and a
half%. Again, a lot of chop, a lot of
names up, a lot of names down. I think
you're going to be seeing that. Uh,
relative to the hyperscalers, the
thematic portfolio relative to the
hyperscalers actually had its biggest
week since late March. That was bigger
than all of these in here. So, it just
highlights to you that this was a bad
week for the hyperscalers.
Uh, thematic portfolio. I showed this
last week. We kind of went under the 60.
Basically, we're right around the 38%
retracement. Um, could it go lower?
Sure. I don't think it will at this
point. Uh, I think we're going to spend
time chopping around here. And if we do,
it'll be minor. Terms of the breath from
a technical basis, again, this was a
warning sign starting to see the change
up here.
Well, we did get to the highest level in
since July 10th. And basically, except
for that one print on that one day on
July 10th, we're starting to see the
breath improve. This is something to
watch, especially if we come back next
week and we get higher on the 20-day.
That is going to be the first sign.
Again, the upward sloping 200 day is
still fantastic. Above the 200 day is
still great. We are still in a bull
market in this. And last week I showed
you um the history of me and head and
shoulders in structural bull markets
which is some of the most powerful
signals come from breaking the neckline
and then turning back up. Now we've done
that so far. Give it some more time and
see what happens. There's a lot of a lot
of leverage still in the system. So it
is highly possible even if it's for a
day print that we break down further
towards the 200 day. As I mentioned I
started buying some last week. I didn't
buy any this week. Uh but I did buy last
week and I will continue to look to buy
as we consolidate around here because I
believe that there the bearishness in AI
is growing again and we go through these
periods and when people get bearish on
it again and I listen to the arguments
and I hear the stuff people are saying
and when I hear things like Anthropic is
done um just because their growth rate
is going to slow that's when I start
getting more interested in things. Um,
in terms of the earnings, this is going
to be the major story. Uh, you're not
going to hear me talk much and I'll get
into the earnings growth, but 86% of
we're almost a third of the way through
have reported and been above. They've
beaten estimates.
3% have been the same, 11 have gone. So,
we're on an 8:1 ratio of beats to
misses. [clears throat] The one-year
average is 80%, the 5-year average is
78, and the 10ear is 76. Again, the
earnings are just coming out across the
board. You're going to see this
repeatedly from me. The profit margins.
Now, again, this includes Google, which
had a one time off. Well, not one time
because it also impacted these numbers
here. Without the Google number, we're
at 14.4. If you take the Google number
out out of here, we're down here closer
to third, closer to 14. So, we are still
progressing higher when it comes to S&P
margins. And that's the major story.
During the week, I did do an update
video for the subscribers and it was on
China. Uh, last night, China sent an
important signal. Capital markets have
become crit critical to achieving its AI
ambitions. It's one of the reasons why I
want to make sure that you guys
recognize this is a race. This is
important to understand. Even though
there's two different goals and I do
agree that China is more focused on open
source and this concept of bringing
abundance to everyone where the US is
still focused on capitalism which I
think is going to run into problems uh
in terms of making money off AI the way
that people think. So I am not a bear on
anthropic but I do believe their growth
rate will never get to the levels that
people had talked about just a month ago
and I think that's an important shift.
So China unleashes broad state support
to halt the tech selloff. This is
important for you guys to think about
because when it comes to the bottom of
of AI, China was heavily involved in
supporting it because they've got their
own issues if their stock market goes
down. China's in the same position as
the US where the stock market is
becoming more critical. Not because it's
a huge part of the investment side
there, but because of the capital needs
and they need a stable market and they
don't have a housing market because
house prices continue to fall in China
every single month and that leads to
instability if they don't have some
asset class going higher and stocks are
a little bit easier right now. China
stateowned funds by nearly 9 billion
shares to support the market.
They're changing listing standards
[clears throat]
just like the US did. So on the IPOs and
getting listed, they are changing to
again get people to get more involved in
these stocks very quickly. It's much
easier to support them if they're able
to get into indices earlier.
Chinese stocks extend rise as
statebacked insurers tout long-term
investments. The latest sign of
government support, five statebacked
insurers say they will continue to boost
their equity holdings. Now, a lot of
this comes from a very important AI
company, the most important AI company
in China, Deepseek. It's founders fund
slumped 16%. So, remember, it's a hedge
fund. So, it was down 16% last week.
Deepseek and China's AI boom are
increasingly powered by state money.
This was in May.
China's Deep Seek closes over 7 billion
funding in June 16th with unusual deal
structure. And the reason it was unusual
is because China's statebacked nor
basically the government is the only
outside party given voting rights. This
is why you can't separate the race.
China's heavily involved and so if the
most important AI company inside China
falls
and China isn't supporting them and they
need to raise more capital which I'll
get into and not just them everyone.
China's AI companies rush to raise funds
and close gap with the US. Chinese AI
developers are racing to raise money
through share offerings or loans,
believing they need a bigger war chest
to keep up with US competitors. Capital
is critical. China's deepseek to raise
fresh capital. They just did a raise.
The government was involved 74 billion
and this is a month later.
Moonshot
of fame chem 3.0. 0 seeks 50 billion
valuation in preIPO rounds. So they're
going to raise money and again I said
this last week.
Anthropic is 23 trillion valuate company
now. This is a $50 billion valuation. No
comparison between being able to support
AI from a big basis. And I'll get into
more of Kimmy K later. Um all of this
capital needs well as I showed last week
and we'll continue. We've got the
hyperscaler bonds are declining. That's
got everyone freaked out. It's hitting
global bond markets. That's got everyone
freaked out. I'm not worried about that.
[snorts] Um SpaceX sets unlock 116
billion. This is all just to show that
again when I went through the reasons
for the midcycle slowdown. One of the
things that was on the headwind list was
the massive amount of capital raises
that were going to come not just from
what's happened so far. Google raised 80
billion. You've got all the Chinese
companies raising money. You still got
Open AI. They've got Enthropic. SpaceX
was done. It should not be surprising to
anyone that the market's having trouble
as all of this liquidity is being soaked
up by issuance. It takes time to digest
it and it comes during the summertime
when there's not much volume or
liquidity as it is and most people are
not around. Eric Schmidt says cash, not
energy, is the real limit on AI growth.
I've seen this chart a bunch. Phil
Rosen, my buddy. Uh, again, I think this
is going to persist for a long time. I
don't think this is anything new. Uh,
but it fits into this. So, this is from
Sundar after the results. And I just
want to make sure there's you can go
through and talk about the free cash
flow. You can talk about the fact
they're not going to make it. This is a
seven slides of just honesty on what is
happening. The first part is you cannot
ignore that their revenue not their
earnings their revenue growth 24% at the
aggregate level 17% still in search
82% [clears throat]
in cloud
and 13% in YouTube ads. Now the reason I
bring that up as you go through this is
because they are absolutely growing as
they're spending money. Their issue is
not their business growing. It is the
backlog because they don't have
capacity. We continue to be supply
constrained.
Evidence of rapid adoption. Demand still
outpaces that investment even after
large capacity.
The company has already spent heavily
and it is still capacity short. They're
expanding third party capacity to
bridge. Again, you think about why Meta
is going through. Meta can't use it.
They don't have the cloud yet, so
they're willing to sell it out to people
because other people can't fill it. This
is exactly what Meta should be doing. If
they can't use the compute for the next
six months, why wouldn't you use it?
You're getting great margins on it.
They're willing to rent more expensive
external compute.
Short-term extensive expensive cap
capacity deal can still be very
attractive if they do it outside. So,
they raise their capex. So, good again
for all the memory and the chip names.
um they're going to continue to invest
as long as they see an attractive
return. On the direct ROIC question,
Google has become more bullish on the
opportunities over the year ahead, and
that's for good reason. First of all,
the cloud is growing at 20 at 82%. The
backlog was up another 50 billion. They
expect to recognize just over half of
that or let's say 260 billion over the
next 12 months. So if they're going to
spend 200 billion and they're expecting
over the next two years to get 200
billion 260 billion you guys can start
to do the overall math over okay they
have a lot of revenue sitting outside
and very few people talk about the
backlog like it's not going to happen I
get into the risk later so let's just go
through this so the free cash flow was
negative operating cash flow was still
39 billion but capex was 45 billion
um this was the first quarter where it
was negative they still have a huge cash
flow but as they continue to spend money
they're depending on the revenues coming
in to keep this fairly close to nothing
so they don't have to go into their cash
reserves regardless this is not some
crazy story they have the ability to
raise money they're not trying to manage
towards nearterm positive free cash flow
so here are the revenues and what I want
you to look is you see the parabolic
move this is not a short move. That's
why it's 82% year-over-year growth. So,
Bob Elliot, you have to think about what
they paid to get it. Since Q124, Google
has generated 30 billion excess earnings
in their cloud unit, but has paid 140
billion in capex to get it.
Okay. So, I take that go through in
Grock and basically ask it for the Bob
Elliott argument for apples to apples.
Since capex is an investment for the
future, shouldn't you include the
backlog growth as well as this is what
the capex is for? And basically it goes
through and you can't ignore it. The
exploding backlog supports the thesis
that returns will materialize over the
five to sevenyear depreciation window of
conversion rates hold.
So again,
this is just a case of investors having
trouble. This is a backlog that grows
from 106 billion to 514 billion in one
year. I mean, that's unbelievable. To go
from 106 billion to 514 in one year is
unprecedented. Makes it hard to believe.
Elliot style concerns reflect difficulty
pricing unprecedented AIdriven
acceleration versus traditional ROI
models. Yet, the backlog in this
basically investors often lag
exponential curves and sustained
execution removes doubt. Now,
to give everyone the honest benefit of
the doubt, let's just go to Fable 5 and
let the smartest LLM on the street go
through and basically tell me what's
going on. And what I wanted it to do was
basically go through the details and
then give me a probability that this is
going to work out well. First of all, it
says the backlog is the whole ball game.
I didn't ask it to say that. It just did
it. They are not spending on faith. The
incremental spending is chasing demand.
They can already see. And the unit
economics are improving as they scale,
not deteriorating. They're literally
renting Nvidia chips from SpaceX for
roughly 920 million a month. This is why
if you don't go in and just type in,
give me the details on and all I asked
it was earnings Google report. Let's go
through the details. Let's go through
the backlog. Let's go through the cash
flow. How should we interpret it? And
then at the end, give me a uh an account
a probability that this makes it. One
honesty note on the corner. The reported
$911 EPS included about 99 billion of
gains on equity stakes. The operational
EPS was closer to 285, slightly below
consensus. The great thing about this,
it's just giving you the honest thing.
And here's what it said. Should they
keep spending? Yes. I'd put roughly 70
to 75% odds that this capback program
proves value or creative over the 3 to 5
year horizon
is the logic. Now it gives you the
downside too why it's only 7075. So this
brings up and this is why guys don't
make everything some kind of absolute.
It's all thinking in bets.
One chip obsolence two offbalance sheet
commitment. So basically they're going
through in the obso obsolescence the
fact that these won't last long enough
and their lives are only really four
years than six. Most people are talking
about them being longer than six. But
let's just assume that that is a risk
which has been brought up. The bal off
balance sheet commitments if you've read
this this week about 1 blah blah blah
trillion of off balance sheet for all
these companies all mentioned in here.
Three, the backlog concentration and
conversion risk. If you believe that
that backlog of 514 billion is mainly
open AI and threat then yeah they have
concentration risks. If open AI goes
bust then they lose that. So there are
those risks associated with it. It's
brought up. The verdict flips not on any
single FCF print but on whether
contracted demand continues. This is the
thing is it's all about the demand side
guys. This is what goes through Jevans
paradox. This is what I'll spend some
time on. Now, I want to make sure this
visual is there because I think your
focus needs to be on the long-term flow.
So, when I spend weeks saying
sentiment has finally gotten to push
back on me on memory and says there's no
way to stop this. When I finally say,
okay, Korea is breaking down and we're
seeing the breath break down. the only
two companies that are going higher when
it was all of machinery, all of
construction, all of those things from
miday.
This is the short-term noise. Markets do
not go straight up ever. Even if you're
in a secular bull market, which we are
for AI, there is no way to say this
isn't a secular bare mar bull market.
The only thing you can say is that it
gets too far ahead. We need to have a
big correction. I don't think we're
going to have a big correction. And
that's the reason why if we do, I'll
start seeing it on some of the signals
within there. I saw it on the one side
and we do have a lot of issuance going
on. So, let me just use an example.
Here's the S&P since over the last six,
five and a half years. We've had a
return since 2019. This includes COVID
15% annualized. Seems like an easy bull
market when you look at the chart.
Here's the rolling 63-day. This is 22
trading days a month. This is the
rolling three-month returns during that
period. Look how many times they not
only go negative, they go negative
double digits. One, two, three, four,
five, six. Every year, we get the
rolling three month down to -10.
Even in a secular bull market of 15% a
year. Now, I think this is going to be
well above the 15%. The reason I created
this is because for the next 3 to 5
years, I expect this to outperform the
S&P by 15% a year minimum. So, if that's
the case, here's the rolling 63day on
the on the thematic uh portfolio. Could
we go down another 20% based on the S&P?
Yes. I don't think that's going to
happen in this because I think a lot of
this first wave was something different.
Do I think once we make another uh leg
higher it can? Yeah. Do I think we'll go
negative during this period? Yes, I do.
If I go back and look at the mag seven,
you'll see the same thing. Three
podcasts for you guys to either listen
to. I will put all these in the
subscriber side in terms of the summary
so you don't have to, but there's a
prompt through them. But I listened to
these three, the all-in-one,
moonshots one, which I thought was
fantastic. I love Emmod Mosto in terms
of uh having his view on not only the
technology from it building an AI
company and selling it but also from a
hedge fund perspective in terms of the
economy a macroe economic viewpoint and
then Stephen Hoe who did forward
guidance those three were all
interesting now if any of you go to
conferences and you go for a multiple
day conference and you hear a couple
companies and then a couple macro
strategists and they all talk about the
same theme.
I wanted to put something together which
I did first in here. Uh I asked I put
all these transcripts into one context
window and the first thing I said was go
through all of them and give me the
overlapping conversation from these
three
and what are the most important points?
And what it gave me was we're reaching
model abundance meaning the models just
keep getting better. They're they're
converging on very similar capabilities
and the price is d is dropping
dramatically. We still have compute
scarcity. So all of these different
things these are the quotes.
Intelligence can be copied powered can
be copied. Powered compute cannot.
Jevans paradox. Cheaper intelligence
means more intelligence consumed. AI
adoption moves from experiments to
workflows only when it is cheap,
private, and controllable. This is the
enterprise adoption moving from token
maxing to token efficiency. And then the
inevitable winner of this thing is
routing, which means it will include
anthropic, but not only anthropic. We're
going to head to routing to the best
place. So that's what you take three of
them. They're all good. It's like having
a brainstorming session with a total of
let's see that was uh probably nine
people. Um and you get that crossside.
Now what I did next uh is using my
thought process. I wanted to create a
mosaic method prompt. So this is
basically creating a mixture of experts
for forecasting. Uh I'm putting this up
on the subscriber side. So the prompt
will be there that shows you what it is.
The human brain is a serial processor.
listen to three podcasts and you
experience
them one at a time. By the third, the
first one is decayed into a few vivid
moments and the connections between
conversations, the exact places. This
gets back to that conference thing. The
most powerful thing is to have a prompt
that basically goes through and gives
you an output based on what you heard in
a summary where all of these little
nuance points that keep coming out in
there, you're connecting back. So think
of this again as using AI as the
conductor of a symphony and each of
these podcasts end up being one of the
people in the seats. So instead of the
first way I did it was just say what are
the most important points that come out.
This is a prompt that literally goes
through and takes the nuances in all of
them even if it's just a minor point and
then gives you a mosaic. Everything that
I like to do in this as I go through
these data is look at the mosaic. If I
think there's going to be a bare market,
then there needs to be a recession. If
there's going to be a recession, there's
certain things I want to see happen,
like credit spreads widening, like
profits already coming down, like profit
margins already coming down, things like
that. Not when they're all pointed
higher, because there's not going to be
any job firing of any big way if profit
margins are going higher. It's simple
things like that. So, if you guys use
it, one thing I would recommend, and I
say this just because the time of the
year, sorry, having trouble getting this
uh
All right, there we go. Took a little
while. Um, it's fantasy football time.
Using this mixture of expert approach,
the mosaic approach, fantasy draft prep
has the exact structure. This method was
built for an ocean of expert talk, a
visible market consensus to beat, and a
scoreboard to settle who was right.
Think mosaic. You're going to have a
bigger picture. This is one way to think
of uh of things in a mosaic perspective.
So I wanted to s uh give you the the
visual of that first context window of
we've got model abundance, we have
Jevans paradox speeding up because we're
having enterprise adoption, we're
figuring out the routing structure. All
of this means
demand continues to go exponentially
higher. The problem is physical
infrastructure cannot scale at software
speed. we will forever be short compute.
I don't know when we're going to get to
that point because as I go through the
rest of this and you guys have to trust
me on one thing. If you hear there's
going to be an over capacity for a
period of time we could have over
capacity. If OpenAI is not generating
the revenue and the market just says
we're not going to give you any more
capital and no one wants to go through
it, it could be a scary time. Again, I
don't think that is going to happen
because they are growing their revenues
and they have a massive cash situation.
But as you go through this, we are at a
point where this is about demand
outpacing efficiency gain. So I want you
to think about the intelligence
commoditization loop. The stuff gets
cheaper. Jevan paradox drives higher
demand.
Demand outpaces efficiency gains. The
physics wall come in. And this is all
before video. I just want you always to
remember how much more video seeing the
world humanoids full self-driving we are
still at the beginning stage and as I
kind of go through the agentic side we
are nowhere on the agentic side either
in terms of adoption so we've got Kimmy
K3 and QE for the mind I wrote this this
week if you didn't get a chance to read
it because of the summertime
definitely read it especially when I go
through this part of QE for the mine
which I'll get into in a little bit.
This is really important. This is the
key thing. Kimmy K3 needs tons of
compute. It is not a small par model. It
needs a lot. I can't use it. Nobody
sitting at home can use it unless they
have a lot of hardware. So this is not
disrupting the business. I use Anthropic
every single day, OpenAI every day,
Perplexity every day, Grock every day.
Every single one of them. Gemini every
single day. Never once. Kimmy K3. Kimmy
K 2.5. Yeah, because it fits on my
hardware. This is You still need the
compute power. Kimmy K3 may be an
important inflection point for AI.
Potentially negative for openthropic
while being net positive for essentially
every other company in the world. And I
do mean literally. Yes, that is the QE
for the mind part which I wrote about
has received far more love than we
expected. Oh, over the past 48 hours,
demand has pushed close to the limits of
our current capacity. We're adding
capacity as fast as we can when we re
reopen new subscriptions. You can't be a
company and be running out of compute.
Sorry, it doesn't work that way. China's
moonshot pauses Kimmy subscriptions amid
hot demand. IPOs coming.
Aaron Levy, who I've referenced a bunch
in here, he posts a lot, but I think
this is important. Um, he referenced
this Daniel Cornum
talking about AI's biggest winners have
the lowest margins.
Low margin businesses may have become
some of the big may become some of the
biggest AI winners. And that's because
even at a cost reduction of less than 1%
of revenue, it can increase profits by
more than 25% because existing margins
are so thin. The main challenge is
employee adoption rather than asking
workers to learn the tool.
They should embed agents. Agents are
coming and this is the stage that we're
at now. The central takeaway is that AI
should be deployed as infrastructure,
not merely software. I want you to think
about this because this is coming now.
And what that means is we haven't really
seen the profit margin benefit for the
majority of companies and some of the
biggest revenue companies in the world
do not have this benefit. So I wrote
this paper in November of last year
called QE for the mind and I talked
about how artificial intelligence is
flooding the economy with intelligence
liquidity. This is what I was talking
about. Under QE and Zerp, companies use
cheap money to engineer earnings. The
playbook was simple. You borrow 2%, buy
back stock yielding 6% and watch your
earnings per share rise even if profit
stood still. This was financial
leverage. But now a mere 5% reduction in
expenses, go back to what I just showed
you in terms of that that post yields a
20% EPS jump. You get far more leverage
with reducing your expenses through AI
and how it flows to the top to the
bottom line. So then I just went into
Fable and said give me five S&P 500
companies that fit the papers frame uh
paperwork. Now this is the paper Daniel
Cornum's paper and it just brings up
UPS, Cisco, Jable, Centine and Walmart.
You can go read what you want but you
can see these companies
they have a lot of revenues but they
have a lot of expensive a lot of
employees. They have a lot of friction
they have a lot of internal problems. So
if you can start to use agents for the
workflows, it's going to have a big
difference. And here's the profit
margins measured in the way one way that
just uses the GDP statistics. So this is
government uh this is corporate profits
from the GDP numbers related to nominal
GDP. So there's another way to look at
profit margins and we're at all-time
highs. And again, the reason I brought
this up with the recessions,
profit margins weaken into. So the.com
bubble, we had already seen this happen.
Profits were already coming down. So
could this happen? Again, it could, but
right now we're nowhere near there. And
you see the lead time on this. So we'll
look at profit margins. It'll be a good
gauge. Earnings year-over-year, they're
just growing. And again, these levels
are isolated to basically times when
we've come out of a recession, except
for the internet boom. Everything else,
you come out of a recession, you have
this boom. This was the housing boom and
the China side. But look what happens
before you go into a recession. Same
thing. It's not just profit margins that
go down, profits go down. Well, profits
are accelerating right now. That's why
it's the critical part for you guys. If
you're going to get bearish on this,
you're taking a low probability bet. Is
it possible? Yes. Is it probable? No.
And if you're betting against bonds,
because the hyperscalers bonds are
widening, they are the best balance
sheets in the world bar none. And you
just saw what Google's numbers were.
Don't look at this stuff in that way.
And don't let this hype that goes
through X's perma bear bare porn get you
in this position. We are in a slowdown.
Everyone got too optimistic. Follow the
technical charts. Follow the the weekly
stuff. There's no reason to chase this
thing at this. This is right now in a
quote unquote mini bare market. We have
30% of the names below the 20-day moving
average. Let's see gradually this stuff
start to go higher. Just another side of
where we were in the earnings last week.
And again, I'm not going to read this
off, but is just to highlight that the
earnings have been explosive. Estimate
revisions factor. So just to show you
how important the earnings are even on a
different basis estimate revisions will
show you weakness before meaning when
the stocks are going down. So I believe
the stock market discounts if we're
seeing the factor of estimate
three-month estimate revisions come down
meaning they go down then it's fine.
Even with the S&P the uh the recent side
we've seen a momentum we haven't seen a
change. So this is overlaid with
earnings per share. So forward earnings
are way way up from where they were.
This is showing you as of now um this
year. This this is a quarterly number at
305. We've taken this number up
significantly. So estimate revisions are
going to be the thing to watch as a
factor and this is where we are all the
way back to 2010. It's almost a direct
overlay. So we've been in this part
since the iPhone came out that estimate
revisions have been the dominant factor
to follow. And right now they're just
saying that stock market's fine. Um,
this is another version of the consensus
beats. And the surprise is again 93% as
of Wednesday. The numbers I got from
fact for Friday were less. Um, again, we
don't have enough compute. So if you
want to find the place, again, the
hyperscalers are spending money. People
don't like the free cash flow. I don't
blame them. there's a 25% chance this
won't work for them. They need to see
their multiple compress for memory and
all these things. These guys are going
to receive money. It's just a question
of when we actually hit peak earnings
and when capacity is going to show up.
I've seen no proof yet that anything can
keep up with the demand. So, let's look
at what's going on to see if anything is
showing that compute is becoming
available. GPU availability tightening
back up. So going right back down to
where it was after a small time where
there was some compute. Um be aware I
don't know if anyone has proven this to
be correct or not but Nvidia according
to the information would be able to make
a thousand Vera Rubin racks per day
which is 630 billion per quarter. Now
I'm bringing this up because Vera Rubin
driving performance per watt lowest cost
token worldwide. We are in the Vera
Rubin spot hits the gas next gen. We are
absolutely in full production.
There's a lot of speculation that they
wouldn't be doing this. So I finally
released the Vera room report that I
spent
all in total I would say three or four
months um really working through it
trying to find companies that were not
part of the 100 name portfolio. Um I
think there's 25 that are not uh o uh
connected to it. they're still going to
be correlated. So, I wouldn't expect you
to go in there and we go through it, but
this will give you guys, especially
hedge funds, um, mutual funds, some more
names to go through on the 800 VDC. What
I did for this was I spent the time
trying to find ones that would have a
step up. This is the critical thing for
the rest of this year. It's the reason
why Marll is still my biggest position.
I believe we're going to see a step up
function in optical and photonics. I
believe that we haven't seen the
earnings flow through yet on these. I'm
looking for beats that are going to be
bigger where we're at the catalyst point
where you can look for where they have
to revise numbers up significantly.
Whether or not that happens for Marll,
we'll see. But at this point, uh I did
buy another optical name this week as
well, AOI.
Um and again, for various reasons, it's
part of the portfolio, but this is
really me scanning and looking for
things that technically look like
they've had a big enough correction and
paying attention to data. I would spend
the time reading this report and going
through it. For those of you who've been
waiting, I did uh post part three and
part four of the research skill
architecture. The way that I go through
and do the work for the Vera Rubin
report. Um a lot the idea for the mosaic
thing came from the mixture of experts
approach that I take in the deep
research thing which you guys have seen.
These prompts will be up this weekend as
well. Um, I just wanted to bring Steve
Hoe up again because I think this one
for those people who really want to
listen to something, uh, if you've
looked at the token index, he's part of
the company now, Silicon Data, that does
a token index. He covers that. I' I've
talked about how that's a ridiculous
index to get bearish on, but he does go
through everything. AI comput is
becoming financial market. Compute
demand should frank men over time.
Enterprise AI likely settles around
orchestration, routing. We've talked
about that. token index is not showing
demand collapse. The market is shifting
from token maxing to token efficiency. I
talked about that. Um cheaper models
they pressure the frontier but they
expand the whole the total market. So
you can see how when you listen to Gavin
Baker and you listen to the all-in pod
and you listen to this. This is the same
story. So don't sit there and say
cheaper models are going to destroy
anthropic. That's not the case. It's
going to expand the total market. The pi
is going to get bigger faster and the
orchestration level will be the smartest
intelligence. So if enterprises start
doing more,
it just everyone gets a bigger piece of
the pie. It's just that anthropic
doesn't grow as fast as it was. There's
there's competition now. Um, and I
talked about that with Pomp. Uh, and how
by 2030, I'm definitely worried about
what will happen to all companies that
are public companies, including
the infrastructure companies. So, this
is not a permable thing. Actually, I
think I'm one of the more bearish people
when we get to 2030, but that's down the
road. And that may change if AGI doesn't
come as fast and if uh we get to a point
where the governments are just making
sure that the public markets keep going.
Remember demand remains structurally
strong. Next phase is enterprise ROC and
this gets into what I wrote about which
is the QE side. I really think people
need to focus on that. I just wanted to
highlight this. Michael Dell put this
out a year ago and this is becoming more
important when I talk to people because
people really believe we're running out
of compute. We're basically in here for
the most part for the agentic side. to
the reasoning side. Video generation, I
just want to show you how much video it
takes because every time I hear people,
I had written a paper on VLMs, so video
language models. Video generation, this
is how much more it is verse baseline
chat. So chatbot to here 10 seconds,
guys.
So how can a movie be? How much more
compute would it take to build a movie,
a full 2-hour movie, which we know is
coming? The compute demands will be
forever.
AI headwinds. Again, I showed this
before. I'm just putting this up because
all of these, there's going to be a
cyber issue this year. We still have the
data center backlash. We've got no
power. We've got cooling issues. We've
got many bottlenecks. We've got
government open source competition. All
of these are going to be there, guys.
That's why it's short-term noise versus
long-term secular boom. As long as
earnings are growing, all this stuff is
doing is stopping it from becoming a
bubble. That's what that stuff is doing.
The friction prevents it from getting
too far too fast. I showed this. This is
the software world. We are in this
world. There is going to be a lot of
things. And if every time these stocks
come down, you start bailing out and
start worrying and you start focused
that Iran and the US are at war again.
Oh my god, oil is going to go higher.
How many times are people going to fall
for they go up and then all of a sudden
when we need them to go down they go
back down. We've got volatility. We're
always going to have volatility. Credit
spreads. We're going to have periods
where credit spreads widen. Right now
might be one of those right now. We're
seeing it with the hyperscaler spreads
going. The world does not end during
these periods. It creates a correction,
but the stocks usually lead and then by
the time things get better, the stock
market's already gone up. So here's the
oil price. This is the December contract
for this year. So, we went almost back
up to the highs. And again, I want you
to look at this. We spent 2023 to 2024
around midpoint of say 68.
Now we're at 78 and people are panicking
when it was could be 200. That was worth
it. It's not worth it. Gas prices, yes,
futures are up here. Gas is continues to
rise. So, are we going to see a a bump
up in the headline CPI? Yeah, I don't
think it's going to be dramatic, but
could we see a bounce back up? Of
course. Here's the 100 day rolling
average or the 100 day rate of change on
crude. So, you can see what's happening
as it is. Like, we already took the CPI
up on the monthly number. There's
We're not going very far, guys. Gas at
the pump didn't come down all the way.
Here's what we're looking at right now
in terms of the inflation print for
July, which would come out in second
week of August, I believe. So, the first
time we're going to see a CPI be nonzero
is going to be midepptember. Do you
really want to bet on that? By the time
we get there, maybe oil is back down.
That's why this is happening. So, the
first time that oil went higher, we saw
one-year inflation swaps go up with it.
Then inflation swaps led the way lower.
They haven't budged, guys.
Smart people are not paying attention to
what oil is doing and saying the
inflation's going higher. Here are
two-year break evens. Tips again. Same
story. War come down. All right, we're
not falling for this again.
Well, I was going to have to go a lot
higher.
Here are those two swaps.
Here's year-over-year CPI over the last
five years. I don't know how many times
to show this. So, if you're worried
about oil and the impact it's going to
have on the Fed and all this stuff,
stop.
Uh, I just want to show you guys this
because now more and more people are
jumping into the Fed and they're going
to have to raise rates. And like I said,
they they may raise rates. We're now 35%
for July. It's not going to kill the
market. Um,
here's wages. Sorry, here's two-year
rates. So this is two-year rates going
higher.
Here is wages median. Here's the
relationship over time. You can't get
past this. The labor market is not
strong. Not when it comes to wages. Not
when it comes to labor participation
rates. Labor force participation rate.
So the Fed is heading into one of the
most unpredictable meetings in years.
And that's because well, no more forward
guidance. Everyone's freaking out. That
means, oh, he could go. He might go. He
might
36% chance. We now have back up to one
and three/4ers by the end of the year.
Here are rates around the globe going
higher. It's not just a US thing. Growth
is good.
CDS on Oracle blowing out. So that gets
people all scared.
$7 billion guarantee. I can't even tell
you how small that number is in a world
of hundreds of billions of dollars. So,
let's move on to the Clarity Act. Besson
says, I think we're at the one yard line
on the Clarity Act in Senate.
Still below 50%. So, they're not
listening to Besson.
David Solomon says it's time to advance
the crypto bill.
My buddy Chris Perkins um
taps new leaders to bridge crypto AI and
traditional finance Bank of America
and someone he used to work with at city
Sandy Call wrote a very important
uh crypto piece
written many pieces on the importance of
agentic AI to crypto and the blockchain
and I'm going to keep telling everyone
who is not spending the time on crypto
By the time a year from now goes on, you
will have spent way too much time
playing catch-up. Go spend the time
understanding why there is no way to get
around that globally the blockchain and
crypto is being accepted by Japan, by
Korea, by every single country. And now
as the Clarity Act is being attempted to
get through, everyone's in a race just
like in AI to see who's going to own
something that is equally as important
as AI, which is the global financial
system.
Pay attention to crypto and the
blockchain. Remember when Mark
Zuckerberg said AI agent tech
progressing slower than expected?
Getting back to Sandy Call's paper, I
want you to think about that in the
context of this movie, 51st Days with
Adam Sandler and Drew Barrymore. And the
reason I bring that up, if you remember
it, this is memory.
So this is an analogy of if you want to
guess why the agentic world is so much
in this point she is a context chat
window only remembering things with
inside that one context window. What has
to happen is in the agentic side, the
amount of memory that's necessary to
store all this and know everything that
he knows, every experience he's had,
everything he's seen, everything he's
connected, songs that he learned when he
was 2 years old. The amount of memory
that's necessary for that from an
agentic side is massive. And that's why
it's taken so long for the consumer
agents to actually be there because you
need to understand the person. If Alexa
is going to talk to me, I don't want to
go back. I want to be able to say not
what's a recipe for this. I want to say
the last time we cooked this together,
what did I do?
Think about all the things in life that
you're just going to put into AI so you
never have to remember anything again
yourself.
S&P just launched its first ever crypto
index in Bitcoin. I went through that
whole thing with 51st days because I
want you to understand that when we get
to the point of the consumer agents, the
crypto side is going to explode in terms
of volumes. Once we get there and this
stuff starts growing, it's going to be
big. So despite everything that went on,
the Clarity Act falling back down to the
30s, all this, Bitcoin had another quiet
week. So it's held the gains. It's still
stable around 64,000.
If you look at it, this is Bitcoin. This
is Ethereum. They're both hanging in
there. They've bounced off the lows.
They are not out of their bare market.
It is still a bare market until we can
break the 200 day moving average on
these. Most importantly, I am showing
this more and more. This is Dogecoin.
Yes, this is a memecoin, but the most
important meme coin. And to me, when
people want beta in the market and they
jump into things like GameStop, this is
a signal that retail is active. The
energy in retail is still non-existent
until we start seeing Dogecoin trend
positively. And here's one way to
measure it. We've been below this the 20
This is a 20-day moving average on
Dogecoin. We've been below it since the
middle of May.
It's now 67 days. This was through
Wednesday.
67 days. The longest in its history.
It matters. We close above it. I think
it matters. Finally, one more. Add
Russia to the list. Parliament passes
law regulating the crypto market. Uh,
that's it for this week, guys. Remember,
if you want to get some more details as
an RA, reach out to Mark Whailing.
That's M Whaling. Mwh22vresearch.com.
We're doing a lot more for RAAS. But
most importantly, everyone is starting
to reach out on the crypto side. I will
be launching the new crypto stuff like
I've talked about in September, late
September into early October. I'm
looking forward to spending a YouTube a
week on that for people who want it. But
more importantly, I think everyone
should be paying attention to what's
happening in crypto. All right, guys.
I'll see you next week.